Charles Habib Malik Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1904-1982 (Box 1-75)
  - Alphabetical File, 1925-1982 (Box 1-51)
    - Jamali, Muhammad Fadil, 1949-1960, undated (Box 25)
    - Jurdak, Mansure, 1946-1953
    - Jurji, Edward J., 1945-1959
    - "J" miscellaneous, 1940-1982, undated, (8 folders)
    - Karam, Raymond Emile, 1945-1949 (Box 26)
    - Keene, J. Calvin, 1949-1962, 1978-1982
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1970
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1963-1966
    - Kettaneh, Francis, 1946-1968, undated
    - Al-Khal, Yusuf, 1945-1973, undated
    - Khayr, Nicola, and family, 1925-1933, 1946-1971, undated
    - Khoury, Angela Jurdak, 1946-1959
    - Khudr, George, 1954-1956
    - Khūrī, Bishārah Khalīl, 1945-1952, 1971, undated
    - Khuri, Hanna, 1925, 1932-1937, 1958
    - Knipp, Julian
      - 1933-1951, (3 folders)
      - 1952-1981, undated, (4 folders) (Box 27)
    - Kritzeck, James, 1968-1975, undated
    - Kurani, Habib, 1947-1961, undated
    - "Kaa-Kas" miscellaneous, 1947-1980, undated, (3 folders)
    - "Kat-Khours" miscellaneous, 1945-1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 28)
    - "Khoury-Ksa" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (7 folders) (Box 29)
    - "Kub-Kys" miscellaneous, 1948-1973, undated (Box 30)
    - Laird, Melvin R., 1963-1976
    - Lamborne, Don R., 1946, 1962-1974, undated
    - Lawrence, Frederic C., 1945-1979, undated, (2 folders)
    - Leavitt, Leslie and Margaret, 1931-1937, 1945-1978
    - Lewis, Clarence I., 1937-1955
    - Luce, Henry Robinson and Clare Boothe, 1952-1972
    - "Lab-Lak" miscellaneous, 1946-1981, undated
    - "Lam-Low" miscellaneous, 1945-1981, undated, (9 folders) (Box 31)
    - "Lub-Lyo" miscellaneous, 1945-1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - MacBride, Thomas, undated
    - Macomber, George A., 1952-1959, 1970, undated
    - Makdisi, Anis E. Khuri, 1947-1957
    - Malfrige, Xenia, 1937
    - Mallouk, André R., 1946-1971, undated, (2 folders)
    - Malouf, Fakhri, 1945-1949, undated
    - Malouf, Ruchdi, 1950-1954
    - Maroun, Jean, 1945-1956
    - Matossian, Zaven, 1948-1973
    - Mattar, Emile, 1947-1970, undated
    - McGhee, George Crews, 1950-1954
    - Melhame, Halim Bey, 1958
    - Meouchi, Paul Pierre, 1957-1969, undated
    - Miller, Franklin, and family, 1969-1974
    - Miller, Samuel H., 1937-1968, undated (Box 33)
    - Mufarrij, Afif K., 1946-1955, undated
    - Musallam, Basim, 1963-1972, undated
    - "Maa-Man" miscellaneous, 1940-1982, undated, (7 folders)
    - "Mar-Mid" miscellaneous, 1938-1982, undated, (8 folders) (Box 34)
    - "Mik-Mug" miscellaneous, 1946-1982, undated, (9 folders) (Box 35)
    - "Muh-Mun" miscellaneous, 1945-1971, undated (Box 36)
    - Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1954
    - Nassif, Anis A., 1949-1974
    - Neumark, John A., 1961-1962
    - Nickoley, Edward F., 1931-1934
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1974, undated
    - "Nab-Nez" miscellaneous, 1943-1982, undated, (6 folders)
    - "New-Nus" miscellaneous, 1947-1972, undated, (4 folders) (Box 37)
    - "O" miscellaneous, 1947-1973, undated, (3 folders)
    - Pharaon, Henri, 1946-1955, 1969-1970, undated
    - Pusey, Nathan M., 1963-1968
    - "P" miscellaneous, 1938-1982, undated, (7 folders) (Box 38)
    - Qaratbāwī, Antoine, 1971, undated
    - Quay, James K., 1931-1937, 1951-1958, undated
    - "Q" miscellaneous, 1954-1976, undated
    - Raragulla, Anis M., 1933-1936 (Box 39)
    - Rayes, Georges N., 1955-1957, undated
    - Rivero, Francisco H., 1960-1982
    - Rizkallah, Joseph E., 1964-1970, undated
    - Rockefeller, David, 1953-1979, undated
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1950-1977, undated, (2 folders)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1947-1960, undated See also Container 176, same heading
    - Rufail, Nuri Anwar, 1933-1935, undated
    - "Raa-Rez" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - "Rho-Rya" miscellaneous, 1944-1981, undated, (5 folders) (Box 40)
    - Saab, Adeeb, 1967-1973
    - Saab, Georges, 1970-1972 (Box 41)
    - Saab, Hassan, 1950-1957, undated
    - Sabra, Fuad, 1951-1971, undated
    - Sadat, Anwar, 1970, undated
    - Salem, Elie A., 1950-1982, undated
    - Saliba, Samira, 1964-1976, undated, (2 folders)
    - Salibi, Kamal S., 1956-1970
    - Saliby, Elie, 1946-1971
    - Sanders, Morris B., 1951-1959
    - Sarquis family, 1947-1982
    - Sarruf, Fuad, 1930-1932, 1945-1972, undated (Box 42)
    - Sarton, George, 1932-1938, 1945-1956
    - Savage, Carlton, 1948-1979
    - Sayegh, Fayez A., 1947-1954, undated
    - Schjelderup, Sonny and Gerhard, 1934-1937, 1947-1949
    - Schmitt, Carl, 1963-1965, undated
    - Schomer, Howard, 1935-1937, 1946-1982, undated, (3 folders)
    - Seelye, Laurens H. and Kate, 1930-1937, 1949-1966 (Box 43)
    - Shakhashiri, Zekin A., 1929-1937, 1948-1975, 1982, (2 folders)
    - Shammas, Shukri Hanna, 1931-1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - Sharabi, Hisham, 1949-1971, undated
    - Sholtzfus, William A., 1949-1957, undated
    - Shuster, George Nauman, 1953, 1962-1969
    - Solh, Sami, 1951-1959, undated
    - Souki, Samyr, 1956-1957, 1964-1973
    - Staub, Albert W., 1945-1950, undated
    - Steere, Douglas V., 1966-1969, undated (Box 44)
    - Stephanou, Evangelos, 1926-1978, undated, (4 folders)
    - Stettinius, Edward R., 1945
    - Strayer, Gene Paul, 1963-1973
    - "Saab-Sale" miscellaneous, 1944-1982, undated, (3 folders)
    - "Salh-Schw" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (6 folders) (Box 45)
    - "Sco-Sly" miscellaneous, 1945-1981, undated, (6 folders) (Box 46)
    - "Smal-Szaz" miscellaneous, 1944-1981, undated, (5 folders) (Box 47)
    - Taky Deen, Sa'id, 1945-1956, undated (Box 48)
    - Tannous, Afif, 1930-1973, undated
    - Thomas, Lowell, 1951-1976, undated
    - Tomeh, George J., 1946-1956
    - Toynbee, Arnold, 1957
    - Tuwayni, Ghassan, 1946-1957, undated
    - Twitchell, H. Kenaston, 1945-1965
    - Tyson, Brady, 1963-1966
    - "Tar-Tan" miscellaneous, 1947-1980, undated, (2 folders)
    - "Tar-Tys" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (4 folders) (Box 49)
    - Usayran, Afif, 1944-1957
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Veatch, Henry, 1947-1958
    - Vrooman, Lee, 1935-1945
    - "V" miscellaneous, 1946-1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Wakim, Khalil, 1945-1970, 1980
    - Wild, John Daniel, 1936-1938, 1945-1967, undated, (3 folders)
    - "Waa-Wan" miscellaneous, 1940-1975, undated
    - "War-Wys" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (4 folders) (Box 51)
    - Yaffi, Abdullah, 1945-1957, 1968-1969, undated
    - "Y" miscellaneous, 1948-1973, undated
    - Zeine, Zeine, 1945-1962, 1970 (Box 52)
    - Zhou, Enlai, 1955
    - Zurayk, Costi K., 1945-1957, 1961-1969
    - "Z" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - Unidentified, 1963-1975, undated
  - Chronological File, 1904-1981 (Box 52-63)
    Correspondence and related material. The bulk of the file predates 1945 and documents Malik's activities through letters to and from family, friends, and associates. Post-1945 correspondence consists primarily of exchanges with family members.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1904, Nov., 1924, Aug.-1932, Dec., (5 folders) (Box 52)
    - 1933, Jan.-1935, Aug., (7 folders) (Box 53)
    - 1935, Sept.-1937, Dec., (8 folders) (Box 54)
    - 1938, Jan.-1939, Mar., (8 folders) (Box 55)
    - 1939, Apr.-1940, Nov., (9 folders) (Box 56)
    - 1940, Dec.-1942, Mar., (10 folders) (Box 57)
    - 1942, Apr.-1944, May, (10 folders) (Box 58)
    - 1944, June-1949, June, (11 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1949, July-1954, Apr., (11 folders) (Box 60)
    - 1954, May-1963, Oct., (11 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1964, Mar.-1974, Dec., (7 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1975, Jan.-1981, Nov., undated, (9 folders) (Box 63)
  - Reading File, 1952-1978 (Box 64-75)
    Carbon copies of outgoing correspondence.
    - 1952, Sept.-1953, Aug., (8 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1953, Sept.-1954, Sept., (13 folders) (Box 65)
    - 1954, Oct.-1955, June, (9 folders) (Box 66)
    - 1955, July-1956, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 67)
    - 1957, Jan.-1959, Jan., (8 folders) (Box 68)
    - 1959, Feb.-1960, Mar., (7 folders) (Box 69)
    - 1960, Apr.-1961, July, (7 folders) (Box 70)
    - 1961, Aug.-1962, Feb., (7 folders) (Box 71)
    - 1962, Mar.-1966, May, (8 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1966, June-1967, Oct., (6 folders) (Box 73)
    - 1967, Nov.-1970, June, (6 folders) (Box 74)
    - 1970, July-1978, May, (6 folders) (Box 75)
- United Nations, 1945-1978 (Box 76-98)
  Correspondence, reports, proceedings, draft resolutions, speeches, statements, notes, schedules, financial accounts, and printed matter pertaining to Malik's attendance at the United Nations Conference on Organization in 1945, his subsequent membership on the Commission on Human Rights, Economic and Social Council, and Security Council, and his presidency of the thirteenth session of the General Assembly in 1958-1959.
  Arranged alphabetically by organizational body, topic, or type of material.
  - Commission on Human Rights (Box 76)
    - Commission sessions
      - First, 1947
        - Minutes, (4 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1946-1947
        - Notes
        - Proposals and draft resolutions
        - Report to Economic and Social Council
        - Speeches and statements by Malik
      - Second, 1947 (Box 77)
        - Notes and drafts of declaration and covenant
        - Report to Economic and Social Council
      - Third, 1948
        - Copy of declaration read before commission
        - Drafts of declaration and covenant
        - Miscellany, 1947-1948
        - Notes
        - Report to Economic and Social Council
      - Fifth, 1949
        - Drafts of covenant, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1948-1949 (Box 78)
        - Notes
        - Report to Economic and Social Council
      - Sixth, 1950
        - Agenda
        - Comments of governments on covenant
        - Drafts of covenant, (2 folders)
        - Lebanese delegation observations
        - Miscellany, 1949-1950
        - Notes
      - Seventh, 1951 (Box 79)
        - Election to presidency
        - Miscellany
        - Speeches and writings
      - Eighth, 1952
        - Communications re alleged human rights violations, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany
      - Ninth, 1953, report
    - Correspondence
      - 1947-1950, (2 folders)
      - 1951-1968, (4 folders) (Box 80)
    - Drafting committee
      - First session, 1947
        - Drafts of declaration
        - Miscellany
        - Notes
        - Record of meetings, (1 folder) (Box 81)
        - Report to commission
      - Second session, 1948
    - Human Rights Day and other commemorative events, 1952-1953, 1968-1978, undated
    - Reports to Lebanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
    - Writings by others, 1945-1951, (2 folders)
  - Economic and Social Council (Box 82)
    - Communications to Lebanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1946-1948
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949
    - Reports, 1947-1948, undated
    - Speeches and statements by Malik, 1946-1948, (2 folders)
  - General Assembly
    - Election of president, twelfth session, 1957
      - Correspondence and proceedings
      - Reports re campaign to elect Malik
    - Presidency of thirteenth session
      - Congratulatory letters and telegrams, 1958, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 83)
      - Documents and notes of general committee and plenary meetings, 1958, (1 vol.); (2 vols.) (Box 84)
  - General Assembly (Box 85)
    - Presidency of thirteenth session
      - Election and opening remarks, 1958
      - Entertaining by Maliks, 1958
      - Miscellany, 1958-1959
      - Telephone messages and travel schedules, 1958-1959
      - World Trade Fair, New York, N.Y., 1959
    - Reports to Lebanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1947, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 86)
    - Speeches and statements by
      - Chamoun, Camille, 1946
      - Malik
        - 1946, Nov.-1954, Oct., (5 folders)
        - 1954, Nov.-1959, Sept., undated, (2 folders) (Box 87)
  - General correspondence
    - 1945-1955, (5 folders)
    - 1957-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 88)
  - Notes
    - 1946-1947, (5 folders)
    - 1948-1961, undated, (5 folders) (Box 89)
  - Radio Division, 1948-1954, undated
  - Security Council
    - Correspondence, 1953-1955
    - Miscellany, 1952-1953
    - Report, 1954
    - Speeches and statements by Malik
      - 1948, Apr.-May, 1953, Aug.-Oct.
      - 1953, Nov.-1954, June, undated, (6 folders) (Box 90)
  - Speeches by other delegates, 1948-1949 (Box 91)
  - Tenth anniversary celebrations, 1955
    - Correspondence, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Programs and invitations
  - Topical file
    - Advisory boards, 1946-1948
    - Atomic energy, 1947-1955, undated
    - Chinese intervention in Korea, 1950-1951, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - Disarmament, 1954-1957, (2 folders)
    - Economic commissions, 1947-1948
    - Freedom of information, 1947-1949, undated
    - Greece, 1949-1950
    - Human rights in Bulgaria, Hungary, and Romania, 1949 (Box 93)
    - Israel and Palestine
      - Admission of Israel to the United Nations, 1949
      - Jerusalem, 1949-1953, (4 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1953-1957
      - Palestinian question (Box 94)
        - Correspondence, 1947-1954, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1948-1954, undated
        - Resolutions, statements, and notes, 1947-1954, undated, (4 folders)
    - Lebanon
      - Miscellany, 1946-1957
      - News reports from press section, 1958, undated
    - Miscellaneous issues, 1945-1951 (Box 95)
    - Morocco, 1950-1954, 1972, (2 folders)
    - Refugees and immigration, 1946-1947
    - Soviet peace resolution, 1949-1950
    - Syria, 1957
    - Technical assistance, 1949-1951
    - Trade unions and other labor issues, 1946-1948
    - Translation of world classics, 1944-1948, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Women's rights, 1946-1948
    - World alliance of universities, 1946
    - World statistical conference, undated
  - Unesco
    - International Fund for the Promotion of Culture, 1972-1974, (4 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1947-1954, 1969-1970, (3 folders) (Box 97)
  - United Nations Conference on Organization, San Francisco, Calif., 1945
    - Committee assignments
    - Dumbarton Oaks Conference, Washington, D.C., proposals
    - Financial accounts
    - General correspondence, (3 folders)
    - Invitations, (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Lebanon
      - Documents prepared for conference
      - Miscellany
    - Naim, Wadih
    - Personnel
    - Press
    - Speech by Malik
    - United States State Department
  - United Nations Correspondents Association, 1950-1958
  - United Nations Day, 1950-1958 See also Oversize
- Subject File, 1930-1982 (Box 98-198)
  Correspondence, reports, minutes, academic files, lectures, conference proceedings, programs, invitations, notes, photographs, and printed matter pertaining to Malik's teaching career at the American University of Beirut, his various diplomatic and political positions in the Lebanese government, and his association with numerous civic, religious, and academic organizations and institutions.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization or topic and chronologically therein.
  - Air University, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala., 1954-1962 (Box 98)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Boston, Mass., 1951-1970, (3 folders) (Box 99)
  - American Academy of Asian Studies, San Francisco, Calif., 1951-1960
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, Pa., 1949-1970, (3 folders)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1947-1974, (2 folders)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1960-1967 (Box 100)
  - American Bible Society, 1961-1969, 1978-1982, (2 folders)
  - American Catholic Philosophical Association, 1962-1980
  - American Council for Judaism, 1952-1967, (3 folders)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1963-1975 (Box 101)
  - American Forum of the Air, 1953
  - American Friends of the College Cevenol, 1951-1957
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1951-1976, undated, (4 folders)
  - American Geographical Society, 1952-1966
  - American Jewish Committee, Interreligious Affairs Commission, 1972-1979
  - American Lebanese League, 1976-1982, undated (Box 102)
  - American Lebanese Syrian Associated Charities, 1960-1962
  - American Management Association, 1958-1962
  - American Middle East Relief, 1948-1954
  - American Philosophical Association, 1951-1975, (4 folders)
  - American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Pa., 1952-1962 (Box 103)
  - American Political Science Association, 1948-1963, (3 folders)
  - American Security Council, 1962-1969
  - American Society of International Law, 1947-1974, (3 folders)
  - American Steel Warehouse Association, 1959 (Box 104)
  - American University, Washington, D.C.
    - Correspondence, 1959-1970, (4 folders)
    - Course material, 1961-1962
  - American University of Beirut, Beirut, Lebanon
    - Alumni Association
      - 1939-1953
      - 1954-1975, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - Board of Academic Deans, 1955-1957, (3 folders)
    - Board of trustees
      - 1946-1956, 1963-1967, (2 folders)
      - 1968-1982, undated (Box 106)
    - Bulletin, 1962-1973, (3 folders)
    - Centennial
      - Advisory committee, 1964-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Program, 1966 (Box 107)
      - Symposia on "God and Man in Contemporary Religious Thought" See also Containers 239-240, God and Man in Contemporary Christian Thought and God and Man in Contenporary Islamic Thought
        - Correspondence and arrangements, 1964-1973, undated, (4 folders)
        - Papers, 1967, (1 folder) (Box 108)
    - Constitution and faculty bylaws, 1938, 1956, 1962-1965
    - Discussion groups proposal, 1939
    - Elementary and Secondary Teachers' Institute, 1955
    - Franjieh, Suleiman, letters from Malik re university affairs, 1968-1975
    - Fund-raising, circa 1939, 1968-1976, undated, (2 folders)
    - General correspondence
      - 1938-1943, (6 folders)
      - 1944-1962, (15 folders) (Box 109)
      - 1963-1972, (10 folders) (Box 110)
      - 1973-1982, undated, (6 folders) (Box 111)
    - June War of 1967, faculty statement to Lyndon B. Johnson, 1967
    - Al-Kulliyah, 1950
    - Long-range planning
      - Program study
        - 1972, Mar.-1973, Jan., (3 folders)
        - 1973, Feb.-1975, Feb., undated (Box 112)
      - Ten-year plan, 1956, 1963-1964, (3 folders)
      - "The University-Horizon 2000," 1975
    - Middle East Group on Intercultural Relations, 1970-1971
    - Middle Eastern Studies, ad hoc committee, 1965-1969, (2 folders)
    - Personnel, 1956-1974 (Box 113)
    - Philosophy Department
      - Annual reports
        - Departmental, 1938-1944, 1966-1967, (2 folders)
        - Malik's, 1966-1975
      - Arabic Philosophical Society, 1943-1944, undated
      - Book suggestions for students, 1939-1940, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1937-1962, (13 folders)
        - 1963-1970, (8 folders) (Box 114)
        - 1971-1975, (5 folders) (Box 115)
      - Course enrollment and majors, 1964-1973
      - Course material
        - Aristotle, 1939-1942, 1956, 1975
        - Augustine, Saint, Bishop of Hippo, 1940-1941
        - Classical Arabic Philosophy, 1938-1939
        - Comprehensive exam questions, 1940-1970, undated
        - Crisis of Reason, 1953-1966
        - Ethics, advanced, 1941-1943
        - History of Philosophy, 1938-1968 (Box 116)
        - Introduction to Philosophy
          - Examination questions, 1938-1944, undated
        - Introduction to Philosophy
          - Lectures, 1938-1944, (4 folders)
          - Readings
            - 1938-1944, (2 folders)
            - 1965-1966 (Box 117)
          - Syllabi, 1938-1944, undated
        - Kant, Immanuel, 1938-1945
        - Logic, 1939-1942
        - Modern Philosophy, 1938-1944
        - Moral Philosophy, 1962-1970, undated
        - Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1938-1939
        - Plato, 1939-1945, 1955-1956
        - Problem of Philosophy, 1938
        - Science, philosophy of, 1940-1941
      - Critiques of program, 1938
      - Curriculum planning, 1937-1944, 1956-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 118)
      - Interdisciplinary programs, 1956-1967, undated
      - Minutes, 1955-1976, undated, (3 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1957, 1965, undated
      - Survey of programs at other universities, 1971, (2 folders)
    - President's office (Box 119)
      - 1934-1964, (7 folders)
      - 1965-1981, (6 folders) (Box 120)
    - Research grant, 1969-1970
    - School of Arts and Sciences (Box 121)
      - Committees
        - Administrative, 1963-1967
        - Advisory, 1945
        - Curriculum, 1955-1956, 1965-1970
        - Department chairmen, 1963-1967
        - Discipline, 1955-1956, 1965-1967
        - Graduate, 1965-1967
        - Group VII, 1937-1941
        - Religious life and studies, 1932-1967, (2 folders)
        - Research, 1939-1944, 1965-1972
        - Scholarships and grants, 1956-1957, 1965-1967 (Box 122)
        - Student life and West Hall, 1938-1942, undated
        - Written and oral examinations, 1965-1966
      - Dean's office
        - 1937-1966, (6 folders)
        - 1967-1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 123)
      - Faculty meetings
        - 1962-1965
        - 1966-1977, (3 folders) (Box 124)
      - "The Idea of the School of Arts and Sciences of the American University of Beirut," by Malik, 1942
      - Ten-year plan
        - Committee interim reports, 1956, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 125)
        - Departmental reports, 1955-1956, (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 126)
        - General correspondence, 1955-1957, undated
        - Notes and statistics, 1956
    - Senate
      - 1955-1956, (2 folders)
      - 1957-1970, (7 folders) (Box 127)
      - 1971-1977, (4 folders) (Box 128)
    - Student unrest
      - 1957-1970, (2 folders)
      - 1971-1977, undated, (5 folders) (Box 129)
  - Argentina and Brazil, trip to, 1962-1963 (Box 130)
  - Asia Institute, New York, N.Y., 1948-1953, undated
  - Asian-African Conference, Bandung, Indonesia
    - Correspondence and invitations, 1955
    - Notes and drafts of resolutions and final report, 1955
    - Statements and background reports, 1952-1955, undated, (3 folders)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Aspen, Colo.
    - 1950
    - 1951-1977, (2 folders) (Box 131)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1952-1975
  - Assumption College, Windsor, Ontario, Canada, 1941-1944, 1952-1953, 1965
  - Augsburg College, Minneapolis, Minn., 1961-1967
  - Autographs and photographs
    - Requests by Malik, 1948-1959, undated, (2 folders)
    - Requests by others, 1950-1955, 1966, 1978, undated
  - "Abn-Aca" miscellaneous, 1949-1974, undated
  - "Agn-Ame" miscellaneous, 1944-1981, undated, (6 folders) (Box 132)
  - "Amh-Azu" miscellaneous, 1946-1976, undated, (4 folders) (Box 133)
  - Baptist World Alliance Youth Conference, Beirut, Lebanon, 1963
  - Beirut College for Women, Beirut, Lebanon, 1954-1973, undated
  - Bitirram, Lebanon, church fund, 1961-1966
  - Boston College, Chestnut Hill, Mass., 1960-1967
  - Boston University, Boston, Mass., 1953, 1963-1967 (Box 134)
  - Brazil See Container 130, Argentina and Brazil, trip to
  - Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah, 1960-1977, (2 folders)
  - Brown University, Providence, R.I., 1952-1953
  - Business Council, 1981
  - "B-Bre" miscellaneous, 1940-1980, undated, (3 folders)
  - "Bri-But" miscellaneous, 1943-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 135)
  - Campus Crusade for Christ International, 1962-1982, undated, (4 folders)
  - Canada, 1952-1958
  - Canadian Institute on Public Affairs, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 1949, undated
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1949-1960
  - Catholic Encyclopedia for School and Home, 1962-1968 (Box 136)
  - Catholic Near East Welfare Association, 1955-1982
  - Charles A. Maguire and Associates International, 1964-1966
  - Charles Habib Malik Educational Fund
    - Correspondence, 1959-1977, undated, (3 folders)